<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Assignments | PSQF 6250</title>
    <link>https://psqf6250.brandonlebeau.org/assignments/assignment/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://psqf6250.brandonlebeau.org/assignments/assignment/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Assignments</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 08 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://psqf6250.brandonlebeau.org/media/blue-balloon.jpg</url>
      <title>Assignments</title>
      <link>https://psqf6250.brandonlebeau.org/assignments/assignment/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Assignment 1</title>
      <link>https://psqf6250.brandonlebeau.org/assignments/assignment/assignment1/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://psqf6250.brandonlebeau.org/assignments/assignment/assignment1/</guid>
      <description>
&lt;script src=&#34;https://psqf6250.brandonlebeau.org/rmarkdown-libs/header-attrs/header-attrs.js&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;div id=&#34;TOC&#34;&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Reproducible Rmarkdown Document&lt;/strong&gt;: &lt;em&gt;10 pts&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Due: &lt;em&gt;February 13th, 2021&lt;/em&gt; - No penalty for late submissions, but due no later than &lt;em&gt;May 8th&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For this assignment, you will create your first reproducible R Markdown document. The source file (the .Rmd) file will be turned in as well as the compiled version (html). The general form of the R code to be included in the document will be given to you. You may be asked to manipulate simple R commands. Submit completed assignment, including Rmd and html to &lt;a href=&#34;https://uiowa.instructure.com/courses/183068/assignments/1629180&#34;&gt;ICON&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;r-markdown-setup&#34; class=&#34;section level1&#34;&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;R Markdown Setup&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;ol style=&#34;list-style-type: decimal&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Using RStudio, open up a new template for an R Markdown file. To do this, go to File &amp;gt; New File &amp;gt; R Markdown.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A new window should open up, type in the details, and ensure that HTML Output is clicked. When finished entering in details, click the ‘okay’ button.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Upon hitting the ‘okay’ button, a document template should show up. Read the elements in the template, then once comfortable with its contents, you can delete it and continue to the questions below.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;questions&#34; class=&#34;section level1&#34;&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Questions&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;ol style=&#34;list-style-type: decimal&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Using Markdown syntax, create a header that says Question 1. Note, you can pick any level of header you wish. Create subsequent headers for each question below. &lt;strong&gt;1 pt&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Create an unordered list that lists your research interests (please list at least 2 interests here). &lt;strong&gt;1 pt&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Create a hyperlink (link to a webpage) that links to the main R project website. Add the link in two ways, one that show the actual link and two, one that has the link embedded within text. You can pick whatever you wish for the link text. &lt;strong&gt;1 pt&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Add a R code chunk to the document. Within this code chunk add the following R code: &lt;code&gt;summary(iris)&lt;/code&gt;. Ensure to give the chunk a unique name. &lt;strong&gt;1 pt&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Using output from the R command used in the code chunk from question 4, create a table that summarizes the first four variables from the output. The syntax to create a table manually can be found in the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.markdownguide.org/extended-syntax/#tables&#34;&gt;Extended Markdown Syntax&lt;/a&gt;. More specifically, create a simple table by hand that describes the first row or two from the output of question 4. &lt;strong&gt;1 pt&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Add a new R code chunk. Inside this code chunk add the following R code: &lt;code&gt;hist(iris$Sepal.Length)&lt;/code&gt;. Ensure to give the chunk a unique name and also add the chunk option to omit the code from being shown in the output. &lt;strong&gt;1 pt&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Create an ordered list with Markdown that ranks your top vacations you have taken. Within each of your top vacations, add a nested item (e.g. &lt;a href=&#34;https://commonmark.org/help/tutorial/10-nestedLists.html&#34; class=&#34;uri&#34;&gt;https://commonmark.org/help/tutorial/10-nestedLists.html&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.markdownguide.org/basic-syntax#lists-1&#34; class=&#34;uri&#34;&gt;https://www.markdownguide.org/basic-syntax#lists-1&lt;/a&gt;) to each of your vacations that states the top activities you did while on vaction. &lt;strong&gt;1 pt&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Write some text that specifies the correlation between the continuous variables from the &lt;code&gt;iris&lt;/code&gt; data. Place the following two bits of code inline in their relevant positions. The two correlations can be calculated with the following bit of code: &lt;code&gt;round(cor(iris$Sepal.Length, iris$Sepal.Width), 2)&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;round(cor(iris$Petal.Length, iris$Petal.Width), 2)&lt;/code&gt; &lt;strong&gt;1 pt&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Let’s now create another figure with the following R code, &lt;code&gt;plot(iris$Sepal.Length, iris$Sepal.Width)&lt;/code&gt;. Similar to above, give the chunk a unique name and also add the chunk option to omit the code from being shown in the output. For this figure, explore the knitr chunk options (&lt;a href=&#34;https://yihui.name/knitr/options/&#34; class=&#34;uri&#34;&gt;https://yihui.name/knitr/options/&lt;/a&gt;) to add a figure caption to the figure. &lt;strong&gt;1 pt&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Add one last code chunk (ensure this chunk has a unique name). Ensure through chunk options that the code is not evaluated, but the code is returned. &lt;strong&gt;1 pt&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;pre class=&#34;r&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;x &amp;lt;- rnorm(100)
y &amp;lt;- runif(100, min = 3, max = 8)
mean(x)
mean(y)&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Assignment 2</title>
      <link>https://psqf6250.brandonlebeau.org/assignments/assignment/assignment2/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://psqf6250.brandonlebeau.org/assignments/assignment/assignment2/</guid>
      <description>
&lt;script src=&#34;https://psqf6250.brandonlebeau.org/rmarkdown-libs/header-attrs/header-attrs.js&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;div id=&#34;TOC&#34;&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Graphics and Data Munging Practice&lt;/strong&gt;: &lt;em&gt;10 pts&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Due: &lt;em&gt;February 27th, 2022&lt;/em&gt; - No penalty for late submissions, but due no later than &lt;em&gt;May 8th&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For this assignment, you will build upon the skills you learned in the first reproducible R Markdown document created in the first assignment. In this assignment, you will explore some data graphically to inform a few research questions using data from the &lt;code&gt;fivethirtyeight&lt;/code&gt; package. The source file (the .Rmd) file will be turned in as well as the compiled version (html). Note, please create a new Rmd document for this assignment rather than continue the one from the first assignment. Submit completed assignment, including Rmd and html to &lt;a href=&#34;https://uiowa.instructure.com/courses/183068/assignments/1629181&#34;&gt;ICON&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All graphics should be of high quality, this includes formatting of axes, axes labels, etc. If none of the graphics are of high quality, a &lt;strong&gt;2 pt&lt;/strong&gt; penalty will apply over and above any item-specific reductions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;research-questions&#34; class=&#34;section level1&#34;&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Research Questions&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The following research questions will be used to guide the assignment, but you do not need to answer these directly. The questions below will reference these questions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol style=&#34;list-style-type: decimal&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Using the &lt;code&gt;college_recent_grads&lt;/code&gt; data from the &lt;code&gt;fivethirtyeight&lt;/code&gt; package, which majors are the most popular?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Using the &lt;code&gt;college_recent_grads&lt;/code&gt; data from the &lt;code&gt;fivethirtyeight&lt;/code&gt; package, which major categories (not individual majors, but bigger major categories, &lt;code&gt;major_category&lt;/code&gt;) are most unisex (i.e., have an equal number of males/females in them.)?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Related to #2, which major categories have the most disproportionate number of males or females with that major category?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Is there any evidence of a relationship between unemployment rate and the popularity of a major? What about median salary (shown by &lt;code&gt;median&lt;/code&gt;) and the popularity of a major?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;questions&#34; class=&#34;section level1&#34;&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Questions&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;ol style=&#34;list-style-type: decimal&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Using an appropriate verb from &lt;code&gt;dplyr&lt;/code&gt;, which majors are the most popular? Don’t print all the data in the output file to answer this question, keep this summary concise. &lt;strong&gt;1 pt&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Which majors are the least popular? Don’t print all the data in the output file to answer this question, keep this summary concise. &lt;strong&gt;1 pt&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Explore the distribution of the variable/attribute &lt;code&gt;sharewomen&lt;/code&gt; visually. Summarize characteristics of this variable in a few sentences. Be sure to include any figure(s) or statistics as evidence to support your description. &lt;strong&gt;1 pt&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Which major categories are the most unisex and which major categories are the most disproportionate? Similar to #1 and #2, please don’t print all of the majors, just highlight a few in each category. &lt;strong&gt;1 pt&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Create a figure that effectively shows which major categories are the most unisex and disproportionate in a single figure. Discuss briefly why this figure is effective at answering research question 2 and 3. &lt;strong&gt;1 pt&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Create a figure that explores if there is a relationship between the popularity of a major and the unemployment rate. Discuss briefly how you defined popularity and why this figure helps to show the relationship between the two attributes. Be sure in your discussion to also state your interpretation of the figure. &lt;strong&gt;1 pt&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Building off of #6, create a figure that explores if there is a relationship between the popularity of a major and the median salary (shown with the &lt;code&gt;median&lt;/code&gt; attribute). Discuss how you defined popularity and why this figure helps to show the relationship between the two attributes. Be sure in your discussion to also state your interpretation of the figure. &lt;strong&gt;1 pt&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Create a figure that explores if there is a relationship between the popularity of a &lt;strong&gt;major category&lt;/strong&gt; and the unemployment rate. Discuss why this figure helps to show the relationship between the two attributes and also discuss how this figure may differ from the one created in #6. What additional features did you need to consider to make an effective visualization of this relationship given the data structure. Be sure in your discussion to also state your interpretation of the figure. Note, you may wish to use &lt;code&gt;dplyr&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;ggplot2&lt;/code&gt; to help with this question. &lt;strong&gt;1 pt&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Create a figure that explores if there is a relationship between the popularity of a &lt;strong&gt;major category&lt;/strong&gt; and the median salary (shown with the &lt;code&gt;median&lt;/code&gt; attribute). Discuss why this figure helps to show the relationship between the two attributes and also discuss how this figure may differ from the one created in #6. What additional features did you need to consider to make an effective visualization of this relationship given the data structure. Be sure in your discussion to also state your interpretation of the figure. Note, you may wish to use &lt;code&gt;dplyr&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;ggplot2&lt;/code&gt; to help with this question. &lt;strong&gt;1 pt&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Identify a new research question from the &lt;code&gt;college_recent_grads&lt;/code&gt; that interests you. State this research question, then create a figure that highlights/explores the research question. Discuss briefly why this figure does a good job of exploring the research question. What challenges did you have creating the figure? &lt;strong&gt;1 pt&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Assignment 3</title>
      <link>https://psqf6250.brandonlebeau.org/assignments/assignment/assignment3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://psqf6250.brandonlebeau.org/assignments/assignment/assignment3/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Exploratory Data Analysis&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;Data Restructuring&lt;/strong&gt;: &lt;em&gt;10 pts&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Due: Around &lt;em&gt;March 27th, 2021&lt;/em&gt; - No penalty for late submissions, but due no later than &lt;em&gt;May 8th&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this assignment, you will perform exploratory data analysis using the &lt;code&gt;gss_cat&lt;/code&gt; data from the &lt;code&gt;forcats&lt;/code&gt; package. The source file (the .Rmd) file will be turned in as well as the compiled version (html). Create a new .Rmd file for this assignment. You also do not need to explicitly answer the research question, rather this is used to guide the first part of the assignment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You also do not need to include the code for most questions in the compiled (html) version since the Rmd will be turned in as well. If a question asks for code or there is particular elements of code you&amp;rsquo;d like to share, you can definitely include those in the final compiled version, but please limit those sections to specific elements rather than long chunks of code. Long chunks of code are best left for the Rmd document.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The source file (the .Rmd) file will be turned in as well as the compiled version (html). Note, please create a new Rmd document for this assignment rather than continue the one from the first assignment. Submit completed assignment, including Rmd and html to &lt;a href=&#34;https://uiowa.instructure.com/courses/183068/assignments/1629182&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;ICON&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All graphics should be of high quality, this includes formatting of axes, axes labels, etc. If none of the graphics are of high quality, a &lt;strong&gt;2 pt&lt;/strong&gt; penalty will apply over and above any item-specific reductions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;research-questions&#34;&gt;Research Questions&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The following research questions will be used to guide the assignment, but you do not need to answer these directly. The questions below will reference these questions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How is age related to the amount of television a person reports watching?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;questions&#34;&gt;Questions&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Does there appear to be patterns in the missing data from the variable &lt;code&gt;tvhours&lt;/code&gt; by different income and age levels? Provide evidence for your reasoning. &lt;strong&gt;1 pt&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Provide a descriptive analysis exploring the research question above. Does age appear to be related to the amount of time a person spends watching television? Ensure in your discussion you provide justification for why you feel one way or the other and be as descriptive as possible. &lt;strong&gt;1 pt&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Data Import, Restructuring, Joining&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this part of the assignment, you will import data and perform data manipulations on this data file.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;questions-1&#34;&gt;Questions&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Read in the &amp;ldquo;ECLS_6250.csv&amp;rdquo; data file from the &lt;a href=&#34;https://psqf6250.brandonlebeau.org/data/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;course website&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Using the &lt;code&gt;head()&lt;/code&gt; function, print the first few rows of the data and using the &lt;code&gt;dim()&lt;/code&gt; function, print out the dimensions of the data. &lt;strong&gt;1 pt&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Verify that the data that are indeed missing are read in as missing values. Use the &amp;ldquo;ECLS_6250.pdf&amp;rdquo; codebook (found on the &lt;a href=&#34;https://psqf6250.brandonlebeau.org/data/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;course website&lt;/a&gt;) to confirm values of missing data for each variable, these are listed for each variable directly in the codebook.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Compute the mean of the following two variables: &amp;ldquo;C4R4MSCL&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;W3SESL&amp;rdquo;. &lt;strong&gt;1 pt&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Using the &lt;code&gt;tidyr&lt;/code&gt; package, convert this data into an extra long format where the variables CHILDID, KURBAN_R, GENDER, and RACE are the id variables. The other data attributes would all represent data values to be restructured.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Using the &lt;code&gt;head()&lt;/code&gt; function, print the first few rows of the data and using the &lt;code&gt;dim()&lt;/code&gt; function, print out the dimensions of the data. Note, you should have 6 columns when you are done with this step. &lt;strong&gt;1 pt&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Using the restructured data from #3 above, create three new variables that represent the type of variable (S = School, C = Child, W = family), the wave number, and remaining information. The type of variable and the wave number are the first and second characters of the variable names that were restructured (i.e. stacked) in #3. Hint, using the &lt;code&gt;separate()&lt;/code&gt; function would be useful for this step and exploring some random rows of the data may be helpful using &lt;code&gt;head()&lt;/code&gt; or &lt;code&gt;tail()&lt;/code&gt; or &lt;code&gt;sample_n()&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Using the &lt;code&gt;head()&lt;/code&gt; function, print the first few rows of the data and using the &lt;code&gt;dim()&lt;/code&gt; function, print out the dimensions of the data. Note, you should have 8 columns when you are done with this step. &lt;strong&gt;1 pt&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Using the restructured data from #4, combine the variable type (i.e., the attribute that is either S, C, or W) and left-over names. This new variable should be similar to the original variable names from when reading in the data from #1, but should not include the wave information in it. Hint, the &lt;code&gt;unite()&lt;/code&gt; function should be helpful for this step.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Using the &lt;code&gt;head()&lt;/code&gt; function, print the first few rows of the data and using the &lt;code&gt;dim()&lt;/code&gt; function, print out the dimensions of the data. Note, you should have 7 columns when you are done with this step. &lt;strong&gt;1 pt&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally, using the restructured data from #5, widen the data set to create a variable for each unique value from the newly created variable from #5.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Using the &lt;code&gt;head()&lt;/code&gt; function, print the first few rows of the data and using the &lt;code&gt;dim()&lt;/code&gt; function, print out the dimensions of the data. Note, you should have 9 columns and fewer rows than #5 when you are done with this step. &lt;strong&gt;1 pt&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Read in the &amp;ldquo;ECLS_6250_school.csv&amp;rdquo; data file found on the &lt;a href=&#34;https://psqf6250.brandonlebeau.org/data/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;course website&lt;/a&gt;. Using the restructured data created in #6, merge the school data imported in question #7 into the child level data. Use the type of join where the number of rows for the child level data are not changed. More specifically, the final data should have the same number of rows as #6, but will add 5 new columns.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Using the &lt;code&gt;head()&lt;/code&gt; function, print the first few rows of the merged data and using the &lt;code&gt;dim()&lt;/code&gt; function, print out the dimensions of the merged data. &lt;strong&gt;1 pt&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This question has a number of steps which are highlighted below in more detail.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Identify the 25 schools at wave 1 that have the highest proportion of female students and create a new data file that has has the school ID and proportion of female students in the school. Note: Use the codebook to identify which code represents males and females. It may also be helpful, although not necessary, to create a new variable for gender.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Perform a filtering join that returns only the rows from the child level data (i.e., the final data from #7) at wave 1 that belong to the 25 schools that had the highest proportion of females at wave 1 (from step one of this question).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Using the &lt;code&gt;head()&lt;/code&gt; function, print the first few rows of the data and using the &lt;code&gt;dim()&lt;/code&gt; function, print out the dimensions of the data. &lt;strong&gt;1 pt&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Assignment 4</title>
      <link>https://psqf6250.brandonlebeau.org/assignments/assignment/assignment4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://psqf6250.brandonlebeau.org/assignments/assignment/assignment4/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Inferential Statistics with R&lt;/strong&gt;: &lt;em&gt;6 pts&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Due around &lt;em&gt;April 10th, 2022&lt;/em&gt; - No penalty for late submissions, but due no later than &lt;em&gt;May 8th&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this assignment, you will explore research questions from an inferential framework using R. The analyses will be more open ended and will likely contain data preparation steps as well. Please turn in the source file (the .Rmd) file as well as the compiled version (html). Create a new .Rmd file for this assignment. If a question asks for code or there is particular elements of code you&amp;rsquo;d like to share, you can definitely include those in the final compiled version, but please limit those sections to specific elements rather than long chunks of code. Long chunks of code are best left for the Rmd document.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The data for this assignment can be found on GitHub and ICON and is named &amp;ldquo;cal-fire-9-10-2020&amp;rdquo;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/lebebr01/statthink/blob/master/data-raw/cal-fire-9-10-2020.csv&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;data on GitHub&lt;/a&gt;. A description of the variables is also provided on ICON. Use this data to explore the questions below. Note, the questions below will guide you through the research questions. You do not need to answer the research questions explicitly, instead you can focus on the specific questions, but keeping the overall research questions in mind may be helpful as you complete the assignment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Any graphics you create should be of high quality, this includes formatting of axes, axes labels, etc. If none of the graphics are of high quality, a &lt;strong&gt;2 pt&lt;/strong&gt; penalty will apply.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;research-questions&#34;&gt;Research Questions&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Is there evidence that the number of acres burned has increased for fires in more recent years?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Does month help explain variation in the number of acres burned over and above the year of the fire?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;When the number of days the fire has burned in added to the model, are year or month the fire started still useful predictors?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;questions&#34;&gt;Questions&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Using text processing, create three new variables in the data that represents:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;the year the fire started&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;the month the fire started&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Create a new variable that represents the length of time a fire burned. This can be created by using the &lt;code&gt;difftime()&lt;/code&gt; function within R. Look at the help page to try to figure out how this function can compute differences in two dates.&lt;br&gt;
The code is sufficient for this question. &lt;strong&gt;1 pt&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Are there any data points that are extreme values or outliers that you feel should be removed from this analysis? Discuss briefly, why you feel these values may impact the analysis and should therefore be removed. Be as specific as you can why any values should or should not be removed. If you identify data that are suspect, remove them from further analysis (i.e. use filter to remove the values). &lt;strong&gt;1 pt&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fit two competing models to attempt to answer the 1st and 2nd research questions. Summarize briefly the results from the models with particular attention to answering the research question so that non-statistics/data science individuals could use the answer for their planning or decision making process. Note, consider carefully the best approach on how to include month and year in your models (i.e., continuous vs factor type variables).  &lt;strong&gt;1 pt&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Which model fits best or do you feel is the best model?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Note, please do not include the output from the &lt;code&gt;summary()&lt;/code&gt; function in your answer, instead pull out relevant information from the output to include in your description.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Check assumptions for the models from #3. Does there appear to be problems with meeting statistical assumptions? Provide rationale for why or why not. &lt;strong&gt;1 pt&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fit another model to attempt to answer the third research question. Summarize briefly the results from the model with particular attention to answering the research question so that non-statistics/data science individuals could use the answer for their planning or decision making process. &lt;strong&gt;1 pt&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Note, please do not include the output from the &lt;code&gt;summary()&lt;/code&gt; function in your answer, instead pull out relevant information from the output to include in your description.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally, create a graphic that summarizes the results from your final model that you feel fits the data the best (i.e. this could be the model from #4 or #7). Discuss why you picked this model and describe why this figure does a good job of showing the takeaway message. &lt;strong&gt;1 pt&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Turning Tables into Graphics with R&lt;/strong&gt;: &lt;em&gt;4 pts&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Any graphics you create should be of high quality, this includes formatting of axes, axes labels, etc. If none of the graphics are of high quality, a &lt;strong&gt;1 pt&lt;/strong&gt; penalty will apply.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;introduction&#34;&gt;Introduction&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Read the article &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.stat.columbia.edu/~gelman/research/published/dodhia.pdf&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Let&amp;rsquo;s Practice What We Preach: Turning Tables Into Graphs&lt;/a&gt;. In this article, Gelman, Pasarica, and Dodhia discuss the benefits of a graph instead of a table to succintly summarize statistical results.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;questions-1&#34;&gt;Questions&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Find a published table showing descriptive or inferential statistic results. Provide a copy of the table (a screen shot is fine for this purpose).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Turn the table from #1 above into a publication quality graphic using R. Ensure that this graphic conveys the same purpose as the original table. &lt;strong&gt;1 pt&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Create a different from the figure created in #3 above, and make an interactive graphic that attempts to convey the same message as the original table. Note, this figure should be an entirely different figure from that in #3. For example, if you created a bar chart in #3, create something other than a bar chart for this question. &lt;strong&gt;1 pt&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Briefly discuss whether you feel the graphs convey the message better or worse than the original table. Use specific examples from the table/graph and recommendations from the article in your discussion. Which figure do you feel does the best job in sharing the original purpose of the table? Be specific in your discussion. &lt;strong&gt;1 pt&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Take the data from the original table, to do this you may need to create an Excel file or use the function &lt;code&gt;data.frame()&lt;/code&gt; to import the data from the original table. Use the &lt;code&gt;kable()&lt;/code&gt; function and &lt;code&gt;kableExtra&lt;/code&gt; package to create a reproducible table that looks as close as possible to the original table. &lt;strong&gt;1 pt&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Assignment 5</title>
      <link>https://psqf6250.brandonlebeau.org/assignments/assignment/assignment5/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://psqf6250.brandonlebeau.org/assignments/assignment/assignment5/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;User Created Functions and Bootstrap&lt;/strong&gt;: &lt;em&gt;10 pts&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Due: &lt;em&gt;May 8th, 2022&lt;/em&gt; - No penalty for late submissions, but due no later than &lt;em&gt;May 8th&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For this assignment, you will write your own user functions to perform a bootstrap. The assignment will guide you through elements to include and functions to look into to create the function for the bootstrap. Note, we have not specifically covered the bootstrap in this course, therefore, if elements are not clear, please reach out for assistance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Please turn in the source file (the .Rmd) file as well as the compiled version (html). Create a new .Rmd file for this assignment. If a question asks for code or there is particular elements of code you&amp;rsquo;d like to share, you can definitely include those in the final compiled version, but please limit those sections to specific elements rather than long chunks of code. Long chunks of code are best left for the Rmd document. Assignments will be uploaded to ICON.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Any graphics you create should be of high quality, this includes formatting of axes, axes labels, etc. If none of the graphics are of high quality, a &lt;strong&gt;2 pt&lt;/strong&gt; penalty will apply.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;bootstrap-procedure&#34;&gt;Bootstrap Procedure&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;First, we treat the sample data as fixed and as the population of interest. For this reason, we hope the original sample data collected is representative of the population of interest.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Generate a random sample of the same size as the original sample, with replacement, from the sample data.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Compute a statistic of interest. This could be a statistic (i.e., mean, median) or fit a statistical model.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Repeat steps 2 and 3 many times.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Visualize or compute descriptive statistics about the multiple statistics of interest computed from step 3.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;code-to-run-prior-to-starting-the-assignment&#34;&gt;Code to run prior to starting the assignment.&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To keep track of the bootstrap procedure, let&amp;rsquo;s add some IDs to the individual penguins from the &lt;code&gt;penguins&lt;/code&gt; data.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-{r&#34;&gt;library(palmerpenguins)
library(tidyverse)

penguins &amp;lt;- penguins %&amp;gt;%
  mutate(penguin_id = 1:n())
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;questions&#34;&gt;Questions&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Create a function that generates a random sample, with replacement, from the original data, &lt;code&gt;penguins&lt;/code&gt; from the palmerpenguins package. More specifically, create a function that accomplishes step 2 from the bootstrap procedure discussion above. Exploring the &lt;code&gt;sample_n()&lt;/code&gt; function may be helpful for this question. For this question, provide the code for the bootstrap function you created and also show the first few rows of the bootstrapped data when you run the function once. The &lt;code&gt;head()&lt;/code&gt; function may be helpful to show just the first few rows. &lt;strong&gt;1 pt&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From a single bootstrap (i.e., using your function from #1), verify that the sampling with replacement is occurring. Use the &lt;code&gt;penguin_id&lt;/code&gt; attribute created from the code used prior to starting the assignment to show that sampling with replacement is working properly. What would you expect if sampling with replacement is working? &lt;strong&gt;1 pt&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Given the function created in #1, let&amp;rsquo;s add a function argument to the function. Add a function argument that allows users to control whether sampling with replacement or without replacement is performed. For this question, the function code is sufficient. &lt;strong&gt;1 pt&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Verify that the function argument created in #3 is working properly by running the function specifying the argument to do the sampling with and without replacement. Use the &lt;code&gt;penguin_id&lt;/code&gt; attribute created from the code used prior to starting the assignment to show that the function argument is working properly. What difference in the output helps to show that the function argument is working properly? &lt;strong&gt;1 pt&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Add an argument that follows branching logic to implement different statistics to be computed to fulfill step #3 of the bootstrap procedures above. You can use any type of statistics you wish in this step, but to simplify this step, compute the statistics for a single continuous attribute from the &lt;code&gt;penguins&lt;/code&gt; data (you can chose the attribute you are most interested in). This would make use of the &lt;code&gt;if()&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;else()&lt;/code&gt; functions discussed in the user written functions portion of the course. The code is sufficient for this question. Note, make sure your function returns the statistic of interest. &lt;strong&gt;1 pt&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Verify that the branching logic and different statistics are working properly from step #5. Run the function for each branch of the function to confirm that different statistics are being computed. &lt;strong&gt;1 pt&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Replicate the bootstrap procedure many times using the following general structure:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-{r&#34;&gt;map_dbl(1:num_reps, function_name, your_function_arguments)
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;where &lt;code&gt;num_reps&lt;/code&gt; are the number of bootstrap replications, &lt;code&gt;function_name&lt;/code&gt; is the name of your function you created as part of this assignment, and &lt;code&gt;your_function_arguments&lt;/code&gt; are the function arguments you may need to pass. You may not need to pass any function arguments to the function above. Note, if your function returns a data frame, you may need to replace the &lt;code&gt;map_dbl()&lt;/code&gt; function above with &lt;code&gt;map_dfr()&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For this question, pick two different number of bootstrap replications and save those two objects. Just the code is sufficient for this question. &lt;strong&gt;1 pt&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol start=&#34;8&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Visualize the bootstrap results for both number of bootstrap replications chosen in #7 using a histogram, density curve, violin plot, boxplot, or some other similar visualization to explore the distribution of the bootstrapped statistic. Are there any differences in the two distributions based on the different number of replications chosen? Why may these differences be showing up? Which number of replications would be more defensible in your opinion? &lt;strong&gt;3 pts&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
