<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Assignments | PSQF 6250</title>
    <link>https://psqf6250.brandonlebeau.org/assignments/assignment/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://psqf6250.brandonlebeau.org/assignments/assignment/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Assignments</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 08 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://psqf6250.brandonlebeau.org/media/blue-balloon.jpg</url>
      <title>Assignments</title>
      <link>https://psqf6250.brandonlebeau.org/assignments/assignment/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Assignment 1</title>
      <link>https://psqf6250.brandonlebeau.org/assignments/assignment/assignment1/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://psqf6250.brandonlebeau.org/assignments/assignment/assignment1/</guid>
      <description>
&lt;script src=&#34;https://psqf6250.brandonlebeau.org/rmarkdown-libs/header-attrs/header-attrs.js&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;div id=&#34;TOC&#34;&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Reproducible Rmarkdown Document&lt;/strong&gt;: &lt;em&gt;20 pts&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Due: &lt;em&gt;February 14th, 2021&lt;/em&gt; - No penalty for late submissions, but due no later than &lt;em&gt;May 7th&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For this assignment, you will create your first reproducible R Markdown document. The source file (the .Rmd) file will be turned in as well as the compiled version (html). The general form of the R code to be included in the document will be given to you. You may be asked to manipulate simple R commands. Submit completed assignment, including Rmd and html to &lt;a href=&#34;https://uiowa.instructure.com/courses/160427/assignments/1375235?module_item_id=4290671&#34;&gt;ICON&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;r-markdown-setup&#34; class=&#34;section level1&#34;&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;R Markdown Setup&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;ol style=&#34;list-style-type: decimal&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Using RStudio, open up a new template for an R Markdown file. To do this, go to File &amp;gt; New File &amp;gt; R Markdown.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A new window should open up, type in the details, and ensure that HTML Output is clicked. When finished entering in details, click the ‘okay’ button.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Upon hitting the ‘okay’ button, a document template should show up. Read the elements in the template, then once comfortable with its contents, you can delete it and continue to the questions below.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;questions&#34; class=&#34;section level1&#34;&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Questions&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;ol style=&#34;list-style-type: decimal&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Using Markdown syntax, create a header that says Question 1. Note, you can pick any level of header you wish. Create subsequent headers for each question below. &lt;strong&gt;1 pt&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Create an unordered list that lists your research interests (please list at least 2 interests here). &lt;strong&gt;1 pt&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Create a hyperlink (link to a webpage) that links to the main R project website. Add the link in two ways, one that show the actual link and two, one that has the link embedded within text. You can pick whatever you wish for the link text. &lt;strong&gt;2 pts&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Add a R code chunk to the document. Within this code chunk add the following R code: &lt;code&gt;summary(iris)&lt;/code&gt;. Ensure to give the chunk a unique name. &lt;strong&gt;2 pts&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Add a line break/horizontal line here now. &lt;strong&gt;1 pt&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Using output from the R command used in the code chunk from question 4, create a table that summarizes the first four variables from the output. The syntax to create a table manually can be found in the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.markdownguide.org/extended-syntax/#tables&#34;&gt;Extended Markdown Syntax&lt;/a&gt; &lt;strong&gt;2 pts&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Add a new R code chunk. Inside this code chunk add the following R code: &lt;code&gt;hist(iris$Sepal.Length)&lt;/code&gt;. Ensure to give the chunk a unique name and also add the chunk option to omit the code from being shown in the output. &lt;strong&gt;2 pts&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Create an ordered list with Markdown that ranks your top vacations you have taken. Within each of your top vacations, add a nested item (e.g. &lt;a href=&#34;https://commonmark.org/help/tutorial/10-nestedLists.html&#34; class=&#34;uri&#34;&gt;https://commonmark.org/help/tutorial/10-nestedLists.html&lt;/a&gt;) to each of your vacations that states the top activities you did while on vaction. &lt;strong&gt;2 pts&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Write some text that specifies the correlation between the continuous variables from the &lt;code&gt;iris&lt;/code&gt; data. Place the following two bits of code inline in their relavent positions. The two correlations can be calculated with the following bit of code: &lt;code&gt;round(cor(iris$Sepal.Length, iris$Sepal.Width), 2)&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;round(cor(iris$Petal.Length, iris$Petal.Width), 2)&lt;/code&gt; &lt;strong&gt;2 pts&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Let’s now create another figure with the following R code, &lt;code&gt;plot(iris$Sepal.Length, iris$Sepal.Width)&lt;/code&gt;. Similar to above, give the chunk a unique name and also add the chunk option to omit the code from being shown in the output. For this figure, explore the knitr chunk options (&lt;a href=&#34;https://yihui.name/knitr/options/&#34; class=&#34;uri&#34;&gt;https://yihui.name/knitr/options/&lt;/a&gt;) to add a figure caption to the figure. &lt;strong&gt;2 pts&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Add one last code chunk (ensure this chunk has a unique name). Ensure through chunk options that the code is not evaluated, but the code is returned. &lt;strong&gt;3 pts&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;pre class=&#34;r&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;x &amp;lt;- rnorm(100)
y &amp;lt;- runif(100, min = 3, max = 8)
mean(x)
mean(y)&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Assignment 2</title>
      <link>https://psqf6250.brandonlebeau.org/assignments/assignment/assignment2/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://psqf6250.brandonlebeau.org/assignments/assignment/assignment2/</guid>
      <description>
&lt;script src=&#34;https://psqf6250.brandonlebeau.org/rmarkdown-libs/header-attrs/header-attrs.js&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;div id=&#34;TOC&#34;&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Graphics and Data Munging Practice&lt;/strong&gt;: &lt;em&gt;20 pts&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Due: &lt;em&gt;March 7th, 2021&lt;/em&gt; - No penalty for late submissions, but due no later than &lt;em&gt;May 7th&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For this assignment, you will build upon the skills you learned in the first reproducible R Markdown document created in the first assignment. In this assignment, you will explore some data graphically to inform a few research questions using data from the &lt;code&gt;fivethirtyeight&lt;/code&gt; package. The source file (the .Rmd) file will be turned in as well as the compiled version (html). Note, please create a new Rmd document for this assignment rather than continue the one from the first assignment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All graphics should be of high quality, this includes formatting of axes, axes labels, etc. If none of the graphics are of high quality, a &lt;strong&gt;2 pt&lt;/strong&gt; penalty will apply over and above any item-specific reductions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;research-questions&#34; class=&#34;section level1&#34;&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Research Questions&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The following research questions will be used to guide the assignment, but you do not need to answer these directly. The questions below will reference these questions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol style=&#34;list-style-type: decimal&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Using the &lt;code&gt;college_recent_grads&lt;/code&gt; data from the &lt;code&gt;fivethirtyeight&lt;/code&gt; package, which majors are the most popular?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Using the &lt;code&gt;college_recent_grads&lt;/code&gt; data from the &lt;code&gt;fivethirtyeight&lt;/code&gt; package, which major categories (not individual majors, but bigger major categories, &lt;code&gt;major_category&lt;/code&gt;) are most unisex (i.e., have an equal number of males/females in them.)?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Related to #2, which major categories have the most disproportionate number of males or females with that major category?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Is there any evidence of a relationship between unemployment rate and the popularity of a major? What about median salary (shown by &lt;code&gt;median&lt;/code&gt;) and the popularity of a major?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;questions&#34; class=&#34;section level1&#34;&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Questions&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;ol style=&#34;list-style-type: decimal&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Using an appropriate verb from &lt;code&gt;dplyr&lt;/code&gt;, which majors are the most popular? Don’t print all the data in the output file to answer this question, keep this summary concise. &lt;strong&gt;1 pt&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Which majors are the least popular? Don’t print all the data in the output file to answer this question, keep this summary concise. &lt;strong&gt;1 pt&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Explore the distribution of the variable/attribute &lt;code&gt;sharewomen&lt;/code&gt; visually. Summarize characteristics of this variable in a few sentences. Be sure to include any figure(s) or statistics as evidence to support your description. &lt;strong&gt;3 pts&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Which major categories are the most unisex and which major categories are the most disproportionate? Similar to #1 and #2, please don’t print all of the majors, just highlight a few in each category. &lt;strong&gt;2 pts&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Create a figure that effectively shows which major categories are the most unisex and disproportionate in a single figure. Discuss briefly why this figure is effective at answering research question 2 and 3. &lt;strong&gt;3 pts&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Create a figure that explores if there is a relationship between the popularity of a major and the unemployment rate. Discuss how you defined popularity and why this figure helps to show the relationship between the two attributes. Be sure in your discussion to also state your interpretation of the figure. &lt;strong&gt;2 pts&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Building off of #6, create a figure that explores if there is a relationship between the popularity of a major and the median salary (shown with the &lt;code&gt;median&lt;/code&gt; attribute). Discuss how you defined popularity and why this figure helps to show the relationship between the two attributes. Be sure in your discussion to also state your interpretation of the figure. &lt;strong&gt;2 pts&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Create a figure that explores if there is a relationship between the popularity of a &lt;strong&gt;major category&lt;/strong&gt; and the unemployment rate. Discuss why this figure helps to show the relationship between the two attributes and also discuss how this figure may differ from the one created in #6. What additional features did you need to consider to make an effective visualization of this relationship given the data structure. Be sure in your discussion to also state your interpretation of the figure. Note, you may wish to use &lt;code&gt;dplyr&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;ggplot2&lt;/code&gt; to help with this question. &lt;strong&gt;3 pts&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Create a figure that explores if there is a relationship between the popularity of a &lt;strong&gt;major category&lt;/strong&gt; and the median salary (shown with the &lt;code&gt;median&lt;/code&gt; attribute). Discuss why this figure helps to show the relationship between the two attributes and also discuss how this figure may differ from the one created in #6. What additional features did you need to consider to make an effective visualization of this relationship given the data structure. Be sure in your discussion to also state your interpretation of the figure. Note, you may wish to use &lt;code&gt;dplyr&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;ggplot2&lt;/code&gt; to help with this question. &lt;strong&gt;3 pts&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Assignment 3</title>
      <link>https://psqf6250.brandonlebeau.org/assignments/assignment/assignment3/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://psqf6250.brandonlebeau.org/assignments/assignment/assignment3/</guid>
      <description>
&lt;script src=&#34;https://psqf6250.brandonlebeau.org/rmarkdown-libs/header-attrs/header-attrs.js&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;div id=&#34;TOC&#34;&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Exploratory Data Analysis&lt;/strong&gt;: &lt;em&gt;11 pts&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Due: &lt;em&gt;March 21st, 2021&lt;/em&gt; - No penalty for late submissions, but due no later than &lt;em&gt;May 7th&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this assignment, you will perform exploratory data analysis using the &lt;code&gt;gss_cat&lt;/code&gt; data from the &lt;code&gt;forcats&lt;/code&gt; package. The source file (the .Rmd) file will be turned in as well as the compiled version (html). Create a new .Rmd file for this assignment. You also do not need to explicitly answer the research question, rather this is used to guide the first part of the assignment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You also do not need to include the code for most questions in the compiled (html) version since the Rmd will be turned in as well. If a question asks for code or there is particular elements of code you’d like to share, you can definitely include those in the final compiled version, but please limit those sections to specific elements rather than long chunks of code. Long chunks of code are best left for the Rmd document.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All graphics should be of high quality, this includes formatting of axes, axes labels, etc. If none of the graphics are of high quality, a &lt;strong&gt;2 pt&lt;/strong&gt; penalty will apply over and above any item-specific reductions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;research-questions&#34; class=&#34;section level1&#34;&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Research Questions&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The following research questions will be used to guide the assignment, but you do not need to answer these directly. The questions below will reference these questions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol style=&#34;list-style-type: decimal&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How is age related to the amount of television a person reports watching?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;questions&#34; class=&#34;section level1&#34;&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Questions&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;ol style=&#34;list-style-type: decimal&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;How is the primary dependent variable (i.e. &lt;code&gt;tvhours&lt;/code&gt;) defined (i.e. what is the &lt;code&gt;tvhours&lt;/code&gt; variable attempting to measure? How many years of data are present here? Hint, looking at help page for the data may be helpful here, be sure to note anything notable about the definition of the attribute. &lt;strong&gt;1 pt&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Explore the distribution of the &lt;code&gt;tvhours&lt;/code&gt; variable. Provide a summary of the distribution in terms of shape, rare/common cases, and variation. Include justification for your discussion of this distribution. This justification may include figures or descriptive statistics. &lt;strong&gt;2 pts&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;How much of the data is missing in the dependent variable (i.e. &lt;code&gt;tvhours&lt;/code&gt;)? &lt;strong&gt;1 pt&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Does there appear to be patterns in the missing data from the variable &lt;code&gt;tvhours&lt;/code&gt; by different income levels? Provide evidence for your reasoning. &lt;strong&gt;1 pt&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Does there appear to be patterns in the missing data from the variable &lt;code&gt;tvhours&lt;/code&gt; by different age levels? Provide evidence for your reasoning. &lt;strong&gt;1 pt&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;What impact do you feel this missing data will have when exploring the research question above? &lt;strong&gt;2 pts&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Provide a descriptive analysis exploring the research question above. Does age appear to be related to the amount of time a person spends watching television? Ensure in your discussion you provide justification for why you feel one way or the other and be as descriptive as possible. &lt;strong&gt;3 pts&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Data Import, Restructuring, Joining&lt;/strong&gt;: &lt;em&gt;9 pts&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this part of the assignment, you will import data and perform data manipulations on this data file.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;questions-1&#34; class=&#34;section level1&#34;&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Questions&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;ol style=&#34;list-style-type: decimal&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Read in the “ECLS_6250.csv” data file from the &lt;a href=&#34;https://psqf6250.brandonlebeau.org/data/&#34;&gt;course website&lt;/a&gt;.
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Using the &lt;code&gt;head()&lt;/code&gt; function, print the first few rows of the data and using the &lt;code&gt;dim()&lt;/code&gt; function, print out the dimensions of the data. &lt;strong&gt;1 pt&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Verify that the data that are indeed missing are read in as missing values. Use the “ECLS_6250.pdf” codebook (found on the &lt;a href=&#34;https://psqf6250.brandonlebeau.org/data/&#34;&gt;course website&lt;/a&gt;) to confirm values of missing data for each variable, these are listed for each variable directly in the codebook.
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Compute the mean of the following two variables: “C4R4MSCL” and “W3SESL”. &lt;strong&gt;1 pt&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Using the &lt;code&gt;tidyr&lt;/code&gt; package, convert this data into an extra long format where the variables CHILDID, KURBAN_R, GENDER, and RACE are the id variables. The other data attributes would all represent data values to be restructured.
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Using the &lt;code&gt;head()&lt;/code&gt; function, print the first few rows of the data and using the &lt;code&gt;dim()&lt;/code&gt; function, print out the dimensions of the data. Note, you should have 6 columns when you are done with this step. &lt;strong&gt;1 pt&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Using the restructured data from #3 above, create three new variables that represent the type of variable (S = School, C = Child, W = family), the wave number, and remaining information. The type of variable and the wave number are the first and second characters of the variable names that were restructured (i.e. stacked) in #3. Hint, using the &lt;code&gt;separate()&lt;/code&gt; function would be useful for this step and exploring some random rows of the data may be helpful using &lt;code&gt;head()&lt;/code&gt; or &lt;code&gt;tail()&lt;/code&gt; or &lt;code&gt;sample_n()&lt;/code&gt;.
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Using the &lt;code&gt;head()&lt;/code&gt; function, print the first few rows of the data and using the &lt;code&gt;dim()&lt;/code&gt; function, print out the dimensions of the data. Note, you should have 8 columns when you are done with this step. &lt;strong&gt;1 pt&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Using the restructured data from #4, combine the variable type (i.e., the attribute that is either S, C, or W) and left-over names. This new variable should be similar to the original variable names from when reading in the data from #1, but should not include the wave information in it. Hint, the &lt;code&gt;unite()&lt;/code&gt; function should be helpful for this step.
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Using the &lt;code&gt;head()&lt;/code&gt; function, print the first few rows of the data and using the &lt;code&gt;dim()&lt;/code&gt; function, print out the dimensions of the data. Note, you should have 7 columns when you are done with this step. &lt;strong&gt;1 pt&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Finally, using the restructured data from #5, widen the data set to create a variable for each unique value from the newly created variable from #5.
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Using the &lt;code&gt;head()&lt;/code&gt; function, print the first few rows of the data and using the &lt;code&gt;dim()&lt;/code&gt; function, print out the dimensions of the data. Note, you should have 9 columns and fewer rows than #5 when you are done with this step. &lt;strong&gt;1 pt&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Read in the “ECLS_6250_school.csv” data file found on the &lt;a href=&#34;https://psqf6250.brandonlebeau.org/data/&#34;&gt;course website&lt;/a&gt;. Using the restructured data created in #6, merge the school data imported in question #7 into the child level data. Use the type of join where the number of rows for the child level data are not changed. More specifically, the final data should have the same number of rows as #6, but will add 5 new columns.
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Using the &lt;code&gt;head()&lt;/code&gt; function, print the first few rows of the merged data and using the &lt;code&gt;dim()&lt;/code&gt; function, print out the dimensions of the merged data. &lt;strong&gt;1 pt&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;This question has a number of steps which are highlighted below in more detail.
&lt;ol style=&#34;list-style-type: decimal&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Identify the 25 schools at wave 1 that have the highest proportion of female students and create a new data file that has has the school ID and proportion of female students in the school. Note: Use the codebook to identify which code represents males and females. It may also be helpful, although not necessary, to create a new variable for gender.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Perform a filtering join that returns only the rows from the child level data (i.e., the final data from #7) at wave 1 that belong to the 25 schools that had the highest proportion of females at wave 1 (from step one of this question).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Using the &lt;code&gt;head()&lt;/code&gt; function, print the first few rows of the data and using the &lt;code&gt;dim()&lt;/code&gt; function, print out the dimensions of the data. &lt;strong&gt;2 pts&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
